Guide to the Nicole Di Bona Peterson Collection of Advertising Cookbooks, 1850s-2000s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University, Durham, N.C., USA
Nicole Di Bona Peterson Collection of Advertising Cookbooks 1850s-2000s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Di Bona, Joseph.
petersoncookbooks
125 linear feet 3786 items
Joseph Di Bona is Associate Professor Emeritus in the Program in Education at Duke University. The collection is named in honor of his daughter Nicole Di Bona Peterson.
Collection spans the years 1851-2005 and includes hang tags, inserts, recipe cards and guides, cookbooks, operating instructions, owner's manuals and other promotional materials addressed to cooking and kitchen arts. Materials in the collection were used to educate consumers and promote the use of a variety of foods (meat; fish and poultry; dairy; soups; fruits and vegetables; beverages); condiments and spices (sauces, bouillon and broths, chocolate and cocoa, baking soda and baking powder); canning jars; small appliances (cookware, blenders, mixers, microwave ovens); and large appliances (stoves and refrigerators). In addition cookbooks were produced to promote various institutions and trade organizations representing various agricultural cooperatives, insurance and utility companies, churches and government bureaus. Included in the cookbooks are articles addressing health and nutrition, home economics, entertaining at home, along with information on first aid, food science (safe handline of meat and dairy, how leavening ingredients work, etc.). Companies represented in the collection include A.E. Staley, Armour, Best Foods, Borden, Campbell's, Carnation, Del Monte, Duke Power, Fleischmann's, French's, General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, Heinz, Hershey, Jell-O, Kellogg's, Kraft, Land O'Lakes, Lever Brothers, Lipton, Metropolitan Life, Nestlé, Oster, Pet Milk, Pillsbury, Procter & Gamble, Purina, Quaker Oat, Sealtest, Swift, Walter Baker and West Bend. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Also, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. Consequently, there may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Nicole Di Bona Peterson collection of advertising cookbooks were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a succession of gifts and purchases beginning in 1995. In addition to Joseph Di Bona, cookbooks were received from other collectors, including Ken Costa and Richard Pollay.
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1851-2005 and includes hang tags, inserts, recipe cards and guides, cookbooks, operating instructions, owner's manuals and other promotional materials addressed to cooking and kitchen arts. Materials in the collection were used to educate consumers and promote the use of a variety of foods (meat; fish and poultry; dairy; soups; fruits and vegetables; beverages); condiments and spices (sauces, bouillon and broths, chocolate and cocoa, baking soda and baking powder); canning jars; small appliances (cookware, blenders, mixers, microwave ovens); and large appliances (stoves and refrigerators). In addition cookbooks were produced to promote various institutions and trade organizations representing various agricultural cooperatives, insurance and utility companies, churches and government bureaus. Included in the cookbooks are articles addressing health and nutrition, home economics, entertaining at home, along with information on first aid, food science (safe handline of meat and dairy, how leavening ingredients work, etc.). Companies represented in the collection include A.E. Staley, Armour, Best Foods, Borden, Campbell's, Carnation, Del Monte, Duke Power, Fleischmann's, French's, General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, Heinz, Hershey, Jell-O, Kellogg's, Kraft, Land O'Lakes, Lever Brothers, Lipton, Metropolitan Life, Nestlé, Oster, Pet Milk, Pillsbury, Procter & Gamble, Purina, Quaker Oat, Sealtest, Swift, Walter Baker and West Bend.
The cookbooks are physically arranged by date and listed in date order in this collection guide, but a sortable spreadsheet of cookbook titles is available for download at the link below:
Download Cookbooks spreadsheet
Categories of cookbooks include:
Alcoholic Beverages
Baking Misc.
Baking Powder and Baking Soda
Beverages
Candies and Confections
Canning and Preserving
Chocolate
Condiments
Cookware
Dairy Products
Fruits
Gelatin and Puddings
Grains, Cereals, Crackers, and Cookies
Insurance Companies
Large Appliances
Meat, Fish, and Poultry
Miscellaneous
Multiple Products
Nuts
Shortening
Small Appliances
Soups and Sauces
Syrups and Sweeteners
Utility Companies
Vegetables
Arrangement
This collection is organized into the following series:
American Cookbooks, 1850s
American Cookbooks, 1870s
American Cookbooks, 1880s
American Cookbooks, 1890s
American Cookbooks, 1900s
American Cookbooks, 1910s
American Cookbooks, 1920s
American Cookbooks, 1930s
American Cookbooks, 1940s
American Cookbooks, 1950s
American Cookbooks, 1960s
American Cookbooks, 1970s
American Cookbooks, 1980s
American Cookbooks, 1990s
American Cookbooks, 2000s
Argentine Cookbooks, 1910s
Australian Cookbooks, 1910s-1970s
Canadian Cookbooks, 1910s-1990s
Chinese Cookbooks, 1980s
Danish Cookbooks, 1993
English Cookbooks, 1900s-2000s
French Cookbooks, 1970s-1990s
German Cookbooks, 1920s-1960s
Hungarian Cookbooks, 1960s
Latin American Cookbooks, 1920s
Mexican Cookbooks, 1977
Phillipine Cookbooks, 1930
Scottish Cookbooks, 1900s-1990s
South African Cookbooks, 1940s-1960s
Spanish Cookbooks, 1962
Missing Cookbooks
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
DiBona, Joseph E.
A.E. Staley Manufacturing Company
Armour and Company
Best Foods, Inc
Borden Company
Campbell Soup Company
Carnation Company
Del Monte Corporation
Duke Power Company
Fleischmann Company
General Electric Company
General Foods Corporation
General Mills, inc
H.J. Heinz Company
Hershey Foods Corporation
Jell-O Company
John Oster Manufacturing Company
Kellogg Company
Kraft Foods Company
Land O'Lakes Creameries
Lever Brothers Company
Metropolitan Life Insurance Company
Nestlé Company
Pet Milk Company
Pillsbury Flour Mills Company
Procter & Gamble Company
Quaker Oats Company
R.T. French Company
Ralston Purina Company
Sealtest, Inc
Swift & Company
Thomas J. Lipton, Inc
Walter Baker & Company
West Bend Company
Advertising
Advertising -- History
Advertising -- History -- United States
Cookbooks
Cookbooks -- History
Cookbooks -- United States
Cookbooks
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records
D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives
J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company Publications
Pepperidge Farm Advertising and Promotional Materials Collection
Wells Rich Greene Inc. Records
- American Cookbooks 1850s, 1
  - New American Book of Cookery and Housekeeper's assistant, 1851 (Box D01, Item 1850sD-0001)
    Category: Miscellaneous
    Company: H. B. Skinner, John B. Hall
    Product: N/A
    Note: Includes articles on cleaning and dyeing, family medicine, recipes for popular washing fluids
- American Cookbooks 1870s, 2
  - Hood's Cook Book, post 1877 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1870s-0001)
    Company: C. I. Hood & Company
    Product: Hood's Sarsaparilla Hood's Saponaceous Tooth Powder
    Note: receipts (recipes) from Mrs. Mayor Stott's 'Practical Cook Book', testimonials to the various ills Hood's cures and the trustworthiness of Hood & Co.
  - Hood's Cook Book Reprint Number One, post 1877 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1870s-0002)
    Note: receipts (recipes) from Mrs. Mayor Stott's 'Practical Cook Book', testimonials, image of the company store.
  - Mrs. Winslow's Domestic Receipt Book, 1874 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1870s-0003)
    Company: Jeremiah Curtis & Sons, John I. Brown & Sons
    Product: Brown's Bronchial Troches, Household Panacea and Family Liniment, Brown's Vermifuge Comfits, Mrs. Winslow's Soothing Syrup
    Note: Appeals to 'mothers'
  - Mrs. Winslow's Domestic Receipt Book, 1870 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1870s-0004)
  - Mrs. Winslow's Domestic Receipt Book, 1878 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1870s-0005)
    Product: Brown's Bronchial Troches, Brown's Vermifuge Comfits, Brown's Household Panacea, Brown's Camphorated Saponaceous Dentifrice, Mrs. Winslow's Soothing Syrup
    Note: Several ads for each product inserted frequently between recipes, says 'all mothers/ ladies/dentists/druggists use/sell it.' Concern for children, desire to be proper mother.
  - Royal Baker, 1877 (Box A01, Item 1870sA-0001)
    Category: Baking Powder and Baking Soda
    Company: Royal Baking Powder Company
    Product: Royal Baking Powder
    Note: poor condition,
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, 1877 (Box A01, Item 1870sA-0002)
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, circa 1870s (Box A01, Item 1870sA-0003)
    Note: color illustration on cover
  - The Handy Cornucopia, 1878 (Box D01, Item 1870sD-0001)
    Category: Multiple Products
    Company: Steele & Price
    Product: Steele & Price products
    Note: Very fragile
- American Cookbooks 1880s, 3
  - Horsford Almanac and Cook Book, 1881 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1880s-0001)
    Company: Rumford Chemical Works
    Product: Horsford's Bread Preparation
    Note: Emphasis on 'healthful food'
  - Ransom's Family Receipt Book, 1885 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1880s-0002)
    Company: D. Ransom, Son & Company
    Product: Family medicines: King of the Blood, Dr. Trask's Magnetic Ointment
    Note: Miscellaneous facts and tips on first aid, farming, tables of weights, etc.
  - Cakes without Eggs, circa 1880s (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0001)
  - Choice Recipes: How to Use Fleischmann's Compressed Yeast, 1884 (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0002)
    Company: Fleischmann Company
    Product: Fleischmann's Compressed Yeast
    Note: Bread recipes.
  - Dr. Price's Cook Book, 1887 (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0003)
    Company: Price Baking Powder Company
    Product: Dr. Price Cream baking powder
    Note: 9th ed., color illustration on cover (French grape harvest)
  - Dr. Price's Cook Book, 1887 (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0004)
    Note: 9th ed., color illustration on cover (domestic scene)
  - How to Cook, 1887 (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0005)
    Note: black-and-white line drawing on cover
  - None Such.', 1881 (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0006)
    Company: Geo. C. Hanford Company
    Product: None Such baking powder
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, circa 1880s (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0007)
  - Aunt Matilda's' Selected Receipts and Useful Information, 1887 (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0008)
    Company: I. L. Cragin & Company
    Product: dry goods store promotion
  - GEMS, circa 1880s (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0009)
    Company: Electro-Silicon Company
    Product: Electro-Silicon cleaner
    Note: line drawings on covers
  - My Favorite Receipt, 1886 (Box A01, Item 1880sA-0010)
    Product: Baking powder
    Note: hard cover
  - Hood's Cook Book. Reprint. Number One., circa 1880s (Box C01, Item 1880sC-0001)
    Category: Baking Misc.
    Product: Hood's Sarsaparilla
    Note: picture of product bottle on back cover
  - Chase & Sanborn, 1889 (Box C01, Item 1880sC-0002)
    Category: Beverages
    Company: Chase & Sanborn
    Product: Coffee
  - Chase & Sanborn... Tea and Coffee Importers, 1889 (Box C01, Item 1880sC-0003)
    Product: Coffee and Tea
    Note: light green cover, pictures inside of native coffee and tea pickers
  - Coffee, circa 1882 (Box C01, Item 1880sC-0004)
    Company: Unidentified
    Note: blue cover, penciled-in comments, color image inside of coffee branch
  - Hood's Cook Book Number Two, 1888 (Box D01, Item 1880sD-0001)
  - J.W. Colton's Choice Cooking Recipes, 1883 (Box D01, Item 1880sD-0002)
    Company: J. W. Lane Dry Goods and Groceries
    Product: Colton's Select Flavors
- American Cookbooks 1890s, 4
  - How to Carve, circa 1890s (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1890s-0001)
    Company: Bay State Milling Company
    Product: Wingold Flour, Hard Spring wheat and rye flours
    Note: Color illustrations of woman carving various meats
  - Canning Preserving and Jelly Making, 1890 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1890s-0002)
    Category: Canning and Preserving
    Company: Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company
    Product: Wear-Ever' Aluminum Canner, 'Wear-Ever' Preserving Kettle
    Note: color illustration
  - Cereal Foods and How to Cook Them, 1899 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1890s-0003)
    Category: Grains, Cereals, Crackers, and Cookies
    Company: American Cereal Company
    Product: Quaker Brand items, F.S. Brand items, Pettijohn's Brand items
    Note: Color illustrations, slogan: 'We Feed the World' -- woman with American flag wrapped around her holding 2 stalks of grain over 2 globes showing all continents.
  - Healy & Bigalow's New Cook Book, 1890 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1890s-0004)
    Company: Healy & Bigelow
    Product: Kickapoo Indian Remedies
    Note: illustrations depict Native Americans in stereotypical activities. Includes lengthy text about Indian history & culture, testimonials from customers, and extensive descriptions of how these medicines work.
  - Enterprising Housekeeper, 1898 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1890s-0005)
    Category: Small Appliances
    Company: Enterprise Manufacturing Company of PA
    Product: Enterprise appliances (spice mills, meat grinders, jelly press, etc.)
    Note: illustrations of each Enterprise appliance, by Helen Louise Johnson
  - Frozen Dainties, 1899 (Box Pre-1900s-1, Item 1890s-0006)
    Company: White Mountain Freezer Company
    Product: White Mountain Freezer
    Note: By Mrs. D. A. Lincoln,, cutaway illustration of ice cream maker
  - Delicious Desserts, circa 1890s (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0001)
    Company: Price Flavoring Extract Company
    Product: Dr. Price's extracts
    Note: color and black-and-white illustrations, including some of harvesting, ethnic workers
  - Sixteen Dainty Desserts, circa 1890s (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0002)
    Company: Schlotterbeck & Foss Company
    Product: Foss' flavorings
    Note: by D.A. Lincoln (author of original Boston Cooking School cookbook), C.M. Dearborn, Anna Barrows,
  - Rumford Cook Book, 1890s (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0003)
    Product: Rumford Baking Powder
    Note: recipes using baking powder, written by Fannie Merrit Farmer, black-and-white illustration of medals awarded product, color illustration of product on back cover
  - Auserlesene Recepte [Exquisite Recipes], 1895 (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0004)
    Company: Cleveland Baking Powder Company
    Product: Cleveland's Superior Baking Powder
    Note: in German
  - Cleveland's Superior Receipts, circa 1890 (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0005)
  - Cleveland's Superior Receipts, 1892 (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0006)
  - Cleveland's Superior Receipts, 1899 (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0007)
    Note: special edition hard cover
  - Cleveland's Superior Receipts, 1899 (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0008)
  - Cream Baking Powder Pastry Book, 1899 (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0009)
  - Miners' Supplement to the Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, 1898 (Box A01, Item 1890sA-0010)
    Note: aimed at miners, others who live and work outdoors
  - My Favorite Receipt, 1891 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0011)
    Note: hard cover, 5th edition, poor condition
  - My Favorite Receipt, 1898 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0012)
    Note: hard cover, 8th edition
  - Pacific Coast Recipes, circa 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0013)
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, circa 1890 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0014)
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, 1892 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0015)
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, 1894 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0016)
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, 1895 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0017)
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, 1896 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0018)
  - Royal Baker and Pastry Cook, 1898 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0019)
  - Steele & Price's Lupulin Yeast Gems, circa 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0020)
    Company: Steel & Price Manufacturers
    Product: dry hop yeast
    Note: story in the back regarding merits of Steele & Price products
  - Table and Kitchen, 1892 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0021)
  - Table and Kitchen: A Compilation of Approved Cooking Receipts, 1895 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0022)
    Product: Dr. Price's Cream Baking Powder
    Note: blurb about Dr. Price's Cream Baking Powder winning the World's Fair Medal and Diploma
  - Mine & Ranch Cookery, circa 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0023)
  - Mine & Ranch Cookery, circa 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0024)
  - Hints on Coffee Making, 1897 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0025)
    Company: Woolson Spice Company
    Product: Lion coffee
    Note: line drawings
  - Crawford Ranges for Palace, Castle, Fortress, and Cottage Styles, circa 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0026)
    Category: Large Appliances
    Company: Walker & Pratt Manufacturing Company
    Product: Crawford ranges
    Note: includes illustrations of a variety of Crawford ranges
  - Marion Harland's Cook Book,, 1894 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0027)
    Company: Prudential Book Company
    Product: Various
    Note: Wakefield series, no. 23, a weekly series
  - Scientific Cookery Klondike Edition, 1898 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0028)
    Company: Willson & Thurlow
    Product: Misc.
    Note: by Miss Suzy Tracy, includes list of provisions for one year in Alaska
  - Ayer's Preserve Book, 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0029)
    Company: Dr. J. C. Ayer & Company
    Product: Ayer's products
    Note: apocathary information
  - Ayer's Home Economies: Odds and Ends from Table and Market and How to Use Them…, 1892 (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0030)
  - Russwin The Sanitary food Cutter, circa 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0031)
    Company: Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company
    Product: Russwin food cutters
    Note: includes parts list, cleaning instructions
  - Food Value of Honey, by Dr. C.C. Miller, circa 1890s (Box A02, Item 1890sA-0032)
    Category: Syrups and Sweeteners
    Company: A. I. Root Company
    Product: Honey
  - How to Test Baking Powder, Illustrated and Explained. Thatchers Sugar of Milk Baking Powder, 1893 (Box B01, Item 1890sB-0001)
    Company: H. D. Thatcher & Company
    Product: Sugar of Milk Baking Bowder
    Note: Instructions for how to test baking powder, praise for the product, recipes
  - Recipes for Jewett Chafing Dish, 1892 (Box B01, Item 1890sB-0002)
    Category: Cookware
    Company: John C. Jewett Manufacturing Company
    Product: Jewett Chafing Dish
    Note: Recipes using the chafing dish
  - Alfarata' Flour and How to Use It, circa 1890s (Box C01, Item 1890sC-0001)
    Company: Yeager Grist Mill
    Product: Flour
    Note: manufactured by J.M. Yeager, in modern (1892) mill
  - Agate Cook Book, circa 1890s (Box C01, Item 1890sC-0002)
    Company: Agate Iron Ware Manufacturing Company
  - untitled, circa 1890s (Box C01, Item 1890sC-0003)
    Company: Chamberlain
    Product: Chamberlain products
    Note: no cover. Comment about Chamberlain product in box at the bottom of each page.
  - Baker's Pure Fruit Flavoring Extracts, Receipts for Cakes, Desserts, Creams, Custards, Candies, etc., circa 1890s (Box D01, Item 1890sD-0001)
    Company: Baker Extract Company
    Product: Baker's extracts
  - Book of Valuable Recipes, 1898 (Box D01, Item 1890sD-0002)
    Company: Arm and Hammer (Church and Company, see also Church & Dwight))
    Product: Church & Company's Soda
  - Cleveland's Superior Receipts, 1894 (Box D01, Item 1890sD-0003)
    Product: Cleveland's Baking Powder
  - Sparkletalia, circa 1890s (Box D01, Item 1890sD-0004)
    Company: Aerators Limited 'Prana' Sparklet Works
    Product: Prana Sparklet siphons
  - Approved Chocolate Receipts, circa 1890s (Box D01, Item 1890sD-0005)
    Category: Chocolate
    Company: Walter Baker & Company
    Product: Baker's Chocolate
  - Salads: How to Make and Dress Them, 1899 (Box D01, Item 1890sD-0006)
    Category: Condiments
    Company: E. R. Durkee & Company
    Product: Durkee Salad Dressing and Meat Sauce
  - Frozen Dainties as made by The White Mountain Freezer, 1898 (Box D01, Item 1890sD-0007)
    Product: White Mountain ice cream freezer
    Note: Mrs. D.A. Lincoln
  - Washburn Crosby Co.'s New Cook Book, 1894 (Box OV 01, Item OZ 1890s-0001)
    Company: Washburn-Crosby Company
    Product: Gold Medal Flour
    Note: Binding in poor condition and pages are extremely brittle. Color graphics on cover illustrating mill and workers, illustrations throughout, includes ads for Chicago Great Western Railway (picture of Negro waiter) and the Great Schichau
- American Cookbooks 1900s, 5
  - Baker's Pure Fruit Flavoring Extracts: Receipts for Cakes, Desserts, Creams, Custards, Candies, Etc., circa 1900s (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0001)
    Product: Baker's Pure Fruit Flavoring Extracts
    Note: Child on cover, addressed to 'the fastidious housewife'
  - Dr. Price's Delicious Desserts, 1904 (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0002)
    Product: Dr. Price's Delicious Flavoring Extracts (one page on Dr. Price's Wheat Flake Food, by Price Cereal Food Company)
    Note: cover falling off, color and black-and-white illustrations of fruits, people, products, desserts, and award received from Louisiana Purchase Exposition.
  - How to Make a Cake and Pastry of Quality, 1903 (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0003)
    Company: Puget Sound Flouring Mills Company
    Product: Olympic Flour
    Note: cover falling off, written by Mrs. Ellen R. Miller, Teacher of 'Domestic Science', testimonial letter from H L. Bowers, Restaurant Manager
  - Ogilvie's Book for a Cook, 1905 (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0004)
    Company: Ogilvie Flour Mills Company, Limited
    Product: Ogilvie's Royal Household
    Note: Montreal, Canada, photographs of the Ogilvie Mills and factories, small decorative illustrations of people and food throughout
  - Sixty One Uses for Salt with Some Comment on the Kind of Salt to Use, circa 1900s (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0005)
    Company: Diamond Crystal Salt Company
    Product: Shaker Table Salt, Diamond Crystal Cooking Salt, Diamond Crystal Bag Salt
    Note: Spokesperson Martha Elizabeth Stuart
  - Tid-bits from Town Talk: A few Reliable Suggestions for Conjuring with the Staff of Life, 1906 (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0006)
    Company: Lawrenceburg Roller Mills Company
    Product: Town Talk flour
    Note: cover illustration of woman with fresh rolls out of the oven.
  - Cow Brand Soda Cook Book and Facts Worth Knowing, 1900 (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0007)
    Company: Church & Dwight Company
    Product: Cow Brand Soda (Dwight's)
    Note: Rusty staples jeopardize binding. Nice color cover graphics of a cow, features almanac tips and facts such as 'Formula for telling a girl's age,' postage rates, how to measure corn in the crib, rules for computing interest, household tips, and other
  - Rumford Everyday Cook Book for the Housekeeper and Student, circa 1900s (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0008)
    Note: For the Housewife and Student'
  - Rumford Recipe Book, circa 1900s (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0009)
    Note: Little girl wearing big fluffy hat on cover. Emphasis on wholesomeness and purity of baking powder.
  - One Hundred Genuine Italian Recipes Easy to Prepare, 1902 (Box 1900s-1, Item 1900s-0010)
    Company: L. A. Roberts & Company, Inc.
    Product: Cream of chocolate
    Note: Oversize, photocopy